<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Netty on The Culture of Code</title>
    <link>https://konstantinpavlov.net/tags/netty/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Netty on The Culture of Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://konstantinpavlov.net/tags/netty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Automatic Reconnection for Netty Client</title>
      <link>https://konstantinpavlov.net/blog/2015/07/08/implementing-automatic-reconnection-for-netty-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 07:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstantinpavlov.net/blog/2015/07/08/implementing-automatic-reconnection-for-netty-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first requirement of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kpavlov/jreactive-8583&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Netty ISO8588 client connector&lt;/a&gt; was the support for automatic reconnect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first receipts I came across was &lt;a href=&#34;http://tterm.blogspot.com/2014/03/netty-tcp-client-with-reconnect-handling.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Thomas Termin&amp;rsquo;s one&lt;/a&gt;. He suggests adding a ChannelHandler which will schedule the calling of client&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;connect()&lt;/code&gt; method once a Channel becomes inactive. Plus adding ChannelFutureListener which will re-create a bootstrap and re-connect if initial connection was failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this is a working solution, I had a feeling that something is not optimal. Namely, the new Bootstrap is being created on every connection attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I created a FutureListener which should be registered once a Channel is closed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netty: How to Initiate SSL Handshake From Client</title>
      <link>https://konstantinpavlov.net/blog/2013/04/23/netty-how-to-initiate-ssl-handshake-from-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 12:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://konstantinpavlov.net/blog/2013/04/23/netty-how-to-initiate-ssl-handshake-from-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had spent some time recently making netty 3.6 sending some message when connection has been established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What documentation suggests to do is to extend &lt;code&gt;SimpleChannelUpstreamHandler&lt;/code&gt; and override method &lt;code&gt;channelConnected(...)&lt;/code&gt;.
It works fine unless &lt;code&gt;SslHandler&lt;/code&gt; is used in the pipeline.
If handler is present, &lt;code&gt;channelConnected()&lt;/code&gt; was never called on my handler.

The problem was caused by client, which did not initialized SSL handshake on connection.
Until handshake completed, no other &lt;code&gt;ChannelHandlers&lt;/code&gt; are notified.
Hopefully, there is a convenient way to initiate handshake on the client. Netty documentation states:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>